Ushiwaka, he's so awesome. Now I'm super pumped up. Let's go!
Oh, I see, Lefty.
Oh, I see.
me
yeah
How you figure it out
Oh
Ah
How did Noya not get that?
Shake it off, get the next one.
Yeah.
No biggie.
Don't worry.
Give us a good one, Tai Chi.
That's going out.
Yes.
Sorry, guys.
Come on, let's go.
Come on, Tai Chi, get us another one.
I got it.
Sorry, man.
That's on me.
Everyone is so nervous.
We're making beginner's mistakes.
Damn.
We need to focus for this is going to be a slaughter.
Don't panic, guys.
Are you guys getting distracted by all the cameras?
Just ignore them.
Listen up.
Get your heads out of your big dumb asses.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
We all need to chill out.
You included.
Sorry about him.
He's using the old trick of meltdown and freak out to help ease the team's nerves, I guess.
I don't really care how they do it.
As long as they can relax and score some points.
Crap.
The ref is going to have it out for me now.
All right, make it count.
Got it.
All right, that went up nicely.
Yeah.
Nice receive.
Pushy walk up.
You got it.
Keep at it.
Pushy walk up.
I'm adjusting.
I promise.
Third time's the charm.
Oh, man.
I thought there was something different about that guy.
Is the guy in the number one jersey left-handed?
I noticed my big brother always comes in from the left, so that must be why this guy comes
in from the right.
That's right.
And it's pretty rare, too, so it feels like he was born to be the ace.
Huh?
The position Ushi Waka plays is called the opposite, located diagonally from the opposing
team's center, so Karashino's opposite would be where Daichi is now.
Depending on how the opposite moves, it can change the synergy of how a team normally plays.
One way to counter that is to put someone like Daichi there.
He's a flexible, all-around player with solid defense.
It's a pretty common tactic in high school games.
Another approach is to put your heavy hitters there, like Ushi Waka.
Opposites don't serve or receive, even if they're in the front or the back row.
Their only real objective is to be ready to attack.
We used to call them super aces.
Dude, I mean, I get that the bastard is all big and tall and has a lot of power and everything,
but does being a lefty really give him such an advantage?
Suppertime!
Nice kick, Tanaka!
Good, we finally scored a point!
Yeah, that-a-boy, bro!
So tell me, what's so special about being left-handed?
Mmm, okay.
Okay, so because players normally face mostly right-handed opponents, left-handers turn out
to be more tricky than you would expect.
So for example, when a solo blocker makes a jump, they align with the opponent's dominant arm,
which ultimately puts them in a position that's about one shoulder-width away.
Under most circumstances, it results in a predetermined outcome.
But if the player jumps purely on their intuition...
A delayed spike!
...they won't be able to block it in time.
What is Karasuro doing?
Have these nincompoos forgotten how to block?
Their dilemma is adapting to a left-handed player,
who's also equipped with top-tier firepower.
That's what makes Ushiwaka a force to be reckoned with.
So Ushiwaka's already earned them four points since we started?
Yeah.
He seems pretty reliable, and they recognize that.
Their goal was most likely to set him up so they could claim an early lead.
Huh? What's that sound?
Oh, that buzzer means it's a technical timeout.
And what's that?
It's a mandatory timeout taken when one of the teams reaches 8 or 16 points.
They mostly only use it in five-set matches.
At least, I think.
This is important, guys.
Listen up.
Blocking is all about finding that sweet spot and the timing.
Even if you realize you can't stop their attacks,
just remember, it's crucial to be in the way.
If all else fails, just make contact.
Let them know you're there.
Yes, sir!
One touch!
Shit!
Man!
Ushiwaka is relentless!
It's okay!
We'll recover!
That's good!
Just keep it up!
Keep reminding him that wall is there.
We'll get our openings soon.
Shira Torizawa has Ushiwaka.
Huh?
Then, Karasuno has me, the comeback kid.
Oh!
Yeah, that's true.
Stopping all of Ushiwaka's attacks won't happen.
And it'll be even less likely we'll be able to get the ball from him.
However, we'll have a shot if we make his impossible spikes playable.
Hmm?
It's called total defense.
Studying his past games, Ushiwaka likes to utilize the cross block.
So we'll find our opening that way.
We'll counter by having Nishinoya here, where the straight path will be.
We'll force him to hit to our libero.
Good timing, guys.
Nishinoya here, Ushiwaka!
Ushiwaka!
Nishinoya never has this much trouble.
This is serious!
I think that's due to the ball's rotation.
When a left-handed player hits the ball, the spin is slightly different than when a right-handed player hits it.
Obviously, you aren't allowed to hold the ball in volleyball.
So the time frame to affect the ball is a very small window.
So in that moment, if your receive is even slightly off, the ball will go off course.
It's a chance ball!
Damn it! I'm so sorry!
Timing is off.
Total defense, huh?
Even getting the timing right on these blocks is far from easy.
Concentrate, guys!
How confident are you about stopping Ushiwaka's spikes?
You know there's no way I'll be able to beat Ushiwaka.
I'm spending too much of my attention on Ushiwaka.
Is Goggles even trying down there?
Where the hell's your fighting spirit, kid?
You fall asleep?
They're starting to link their attacks together pretty well now.
We have to hurry up and get that big jerk under control!
I sure hope they can learn to go against their muscle memory.
They're used to blocking right-hand shots.
My bad!
Don't worry!
Yeah, well, at least my brother is the type of player who remains calm in high-pressure situations.
Asi, you got this!
He doesn't believe in his own strengths.
Or trust his instincts, either.
Nice receive!
Shouldn't you help build his confidence?
I meant it as praise!
You see, with my brother, he doesn't ever lose his composure.
The only information he knows he can trust is what is directly in his line of sight.
Okay.
I saw that my brother adjusted to the left to put himself in the spike's path.
What happened there?
You're getting really close.
You're actually able to react to what he's sending over.
I have a feeling these are not his full power spikes.
He's probably still just warming up his engine.
He also seems to be focusing on finding ways to get his spikes through all of our blocking.
Back at middle school?
We used to have a lefty on the team.
Man, it was hard to set that guy up.
So, with Ushiwaka's attacks, even a love tap could turn out to be a deadly weapon.
Suki!
Did you get a stinger on your finger?
Uh, yeah.
How unfortunate that you worded it that way.
Here.
Let me help.
Thank you.
This is a pretty common injury, isn't it?
I feel pretty lucky that I barely even nicked it.
That should do it.
Thanks.
Did I even flinch?
No.
I realized after I jumped that I was going to fail.
It's pretty obvious now that I think about it.
You guys are looking mighty stiff!
Let's all just relax, okay?
Uh-huh.
Huh?
Our research showed that Ushiwaka's serves are solid, right?
While he doesn't have the same monstrous attack or precision as Oikawa,
there's still a lot of power behind his shots.
No sense!
Yeah, nice!
I just don't get it.
He's in high school?
This is getting hard to watch.
I hope our guys don't let it bring him down.
Sorry, send me another!
Roger that!
I'm glad I'm not in the position to receive one of his serves.
There's no way I could take that head-on.
Shira Torzawa totally shut us down this set.
We should take this one as a lost cause and save our energy for the next.
Come on.
Keep it going!
Come on!
Do it!
It's up!
Let's go!
We'll be right back.
Nice ball, Kageyama!
Kageyama even faked me out with that play.
Well, he made us a promise and he came through again.
I'm so proud of him.
Can't believe he motioned for the spike, but then made us set.
That guy's truly a disciple of Oikawa.
Huh? Oh, is that so?
How disgusting.
Look at you, Mr. Cool as a Cucumber!
What you thinking?
Yeah, well, no one rattles me more than that asshole Oikawa.
So that's how your brain works.
All right!
My turn to fight!
Look!
He does his in!
He must be thrilled.
I wonder if they're going to keep rotating him to the back like last time.
Get him some points!
Okay, let's do this!
There really isn't much to you.
I guess that's why they stick you in as the middle blocker.
He really doesn't go for any of the serves.
Looks like he's getting ready for a back row attack.
A one-man decode attack.
Do you like that?
Give us a good one!
He's out!
Excellent call!
Keep taking advantage of Shiratoi Zawa's mistakes!
We'll be able to break through!
Great job!
Yeah!
Good old reliable Kageyama and Nishinoya.
They always give us everything they've got.
Yeah.
I hope Ushiwaka noticed my super straight shot!
Nice receive, man.
Thanks, but I couldn't return it.
We really should look for validation elsewhere.
Let's do it, Kageyama.
Yeah.
Ushiwaka!
Hell yeah!
He got it!
Damn, these are so hard to get.
Hinata!
Get last hit!
The ball ricocheted!
They should be able to get to that.
One more time, guys!
I'm Shouyo Hinata from the Karasuno parking lot.
And I'm going to Nationals after I kick your ass.
Oh, come on!
He doesn't do that!
Over to me.
HushouWaka!
Well, now, is Mr. Sirius over there getting his little undies all twisted up?
Color me intrigued!
Don't worry, we're just getting started!
Take this out!
Suck it up, boys!
Hey, Ishiwaka, are you in Karasuno's number 10 buds?
I met him on the street.
The street?
He told me he was going to beat me and go to nationals.
I'll see!
Yeah.
It is.
Come to think of it, didn't you get scolded for letting some strange kid into the school?
Oh, okay!
He's a mouthy kid who picks fights?
I get why you like him so much!
Actually, I hate him.
I loathe arrogance with nothing to back it up.
Huh?
Did my ears deceive me?
If Shorty can make the great stoic Ushiwaka have an emotional response like that...
It sounds like this could be a lot of fun for me as well.
There's nothing to worry about.
You might as well consider that first set your warm-up match.
Ushiwaka scored 11 points, which was nearly half of their overall total.
But the fact that he's getting the ball so often...
Proves that you guys are getting under Shira Torizawa's skin.
They are using him as a crutch.
And he may not seem like it.
But Ushiwaka's a normal human, with normal human limits to his stamina.
So keep wearing him down by using those indirect attacks.
Now get out there and kick some asses!
Right!
You guys are going down!
Let's start off strong, Goshki!
Right!
There it is.
Oh!
Okay.
Synchronized attack!
Wait.
Are all four of them going to attack?
You're right!
Go, go, Russell, go!
Push it, push it!
Well, that was kind of misleading.
This will be interesting.
Serve it where the sun don't shine!
I got it!
Nice receive!
Nice!
Yeah!
They're getting what they want.
They're executing plays without using Ushiwaka, which means that they're feeling pretty comfortable right now.
If their center line joins in and starts attacking us, then of course we'll have too much to deal with and it'll mean big trouble.
Our focus is the same.
All eyes should be on Shira Torizawa's captain Ushiwaka.
So most importantly, we need to create a strategy to nullify his attack.
Otherwise, we don't stand a chance.
We need to keep wearing him down, one attack after another.
Everything depends on it.
All right, he's patched it.
Ushiwaka!
Nice to meet you!
Shake it off, Noya.
Even if they steal warrants, we need to stick to our guns, right, coach?
Right.
Ushiwaka!
It's already that punch serve again!
Do it, Ushiwaka!
Just as planned!
Those tears planned, too?
Awesome, Tanaka!
Okay, we're staying with them, Miss Zip!
Karasuno will have this in the bag if they can get accustomed to Ushiwaka's left-handed shots.
She'll be begging for mercy when I'm done with you, Ushiwaka!
Did something happen between Hinata and Ushiwaka?
Apparently, the two of them butted heads over something.
Huh?
He's gonna give our school a bad name doing stupid crap like that.
Don't play it safe.
Don't be cowards.
And don't hold back.
This is our only way through this.
Ah!
Chance ball!
Pass it to me!
It's his diagonal jump again.
You're gonna have to come through me first if you want to take down Ushiwaka, shall we?
See you later.
E
チャンスはそこにある
あとは君次第です
あとは君次第
一人走願いを叶えるもん
黙って明日を迎えるもん
あとは君次第
今はゆとりもないし
悟るには早い
風の色目に染みる
ゆとり思って
悟り詰め込んで
誇り高く生きたい
No doubt
あとは君次第です
全部君次第
きっと甘い甘いと言われても
違うよ違うとけなされたって
あとは君次第
迷うんじゃない
ラララララララ
君次第
タイチュウ
ゲスモンスター
すごく